Guide to the the Stuart Wright Bibliographic Collection of George Garrett, 1951-1993 RL.00436
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches, 1951-1993 and undated
  - Writings and Speeches, 1985-1988 (Box 8)
    - Quarterly West, Wine Talking, 1985, Spring/Summer (Box 8)
    - The Texas Review, Ruthe-Ann, 1985, Spring/Summer (Box 8)
    - The South Carolina Review, Dixie Dreamland, 1985, Fall (Box 8)
    - The Texas Review, 1985, Fall/Winter (guest fiction editor) (Box 8)
    - Kaisa Kilponen (foreword written by Garrett), 1985 (Box 8)
    - The Fugitives, The Agrarians and Other Twentieth-Century Southern Writers, George Garrett, 1985 (Box 8)
    - The Georgia Review, The Confidence Man, 1986, Spring (Box 8)
    - Western Humanities Review, Recent Fiction, 1986, Summer (Box 8)
    - The Hollins Critic, Slavitt's The Tristia of Orid, 1986, Dec. (Box 8)
    - The Chattahoochee Review, Genius Baby, 1986, Winter (Box 8)
    - Bred Any Good Rooks Lately?, Lupe has the Last Word, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Chronicles, A (Pardon the Expression) Baccalaureate Address, 1987, Sept. (Box 8)
    - The World and I, Taking Flight, 1987, Sept. (Box 8)
    - Poetry Pilot, 1987, Oct. (guest ed.) (Box 8)
    - The Sewanee Review, American Publishing: Then and Now, 1987, Spring (Box 8)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, My Two One-Eyed Coaches, 1987, Spring (Box 8)
    - St. Andrew's Sewanee School News, Lou-Two, 1987, Summer (Box 8)
    - Michigan Quarterly Review, The Start System: A Jeremiad, 1987, Fall (Box 8)
    - Contemporary New England Poetry: A Sampler (foreword by Garrett), 1987 (Box 8)
    - The World and I, A Singular View of New York, 1988, Jan. (Box 8)
    - The Texas Review, Nominations for Oblivion, 1988, Spring/Summer (Box 8)
    - The Cream City Review, The Long and Short of It, 1988, Summer (Box 8)
    - The Sewanee Review, American Publishing Now, 1988, Summer (Box 8)
    - The Review of Contemporary Fiction, Once More Unto the Breach, Dear Friends, Once More, 1988, Fall (Box 8)
    - The Best American Essays, My Two One-Eyed Coaches, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Contemporary New England Poetry: A Sampler Vol. II, Main Weathers, Fall Landscape, New England, 1988 (Box 8)
    - New Virginia Review, Tears for a Perfect Stranger, Captain Barfoot..., 1988 (Box 8)
    - Ploughshares, Yolanda Barnes, 1988 (Box 8)
    - The Southern California Anthology, Crowfoot, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Three Rivers Poetry Journal, A Dear John Letter, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1989-1991
    - Chronicles, Voices, 1989, May (Box 9)
    - The World and I, The Many Splendors of 'Country', 1989, June (Box 9)
    - Chronicles, Good as Goldwyn, 1989, Aug. (Box 9)
    - The World and I, So Serious it was Ridiculous, 1989, Nov. (Box 9)
    - Poetry Alive!, For A Bitter Season, 1989, 3 Dec. (Box 9)
    - Black Warrior Review, A Very Small One, 1989, Spring (Box 9)
    - The Wooster Review, Whistling in the Dark..., 1989, Spring (Box 9)
    - New Literary History, The Sorrows of Fat City; On Eclecticism and Other Bad Habits, 1989, Autumn (Box 9)
    - Shenandoah, The Pamphlet, 1989, Fall (Box 9)
    - Creative Writing in America, The Future of Creative Writing Programs, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Albemarle, Shepard Adventure, 1989, Dec.-1990, Jan. (Box 9)
    - The World and I, Memorable Effects, 1990, Feb. (Box 9)
    - Chronicles, Art is Always Political..., 1990, Apr. (Box 9)
    - Chronicles, Inch by Inch, 1990, Jun. (Box 9)
    - The Hollins Critic, Review of several John Ciardi works, 1990, June (Box 9)
    - The World and I, Portrait of an Artist, 1990, Aug. (Box 9)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, Captain Barfoot..., 1990, Spring (Box 9)
    - The Sewanee Review, Vellieties and Vicissitudes, 1990, Fall (Box 9)
    - Contemporary Southern Short Fiction: A Sampler, 1990, Fall/Winter (Box 9)
    - Eric Clapton's Lover and other Stories, 1990(2 copies) (Box 9)
    - Located Lives, Uncles and Others, 1990 (Box 9)
    - The Missouri Review, Uncles and Others, 1990 (Box 9)
    - The Writer's Mind, Interviews with American Authors, 1990 (Box 9)
    - The World and I, Finding Peace, 1991, Aug (Box 9)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1991-1993 and undated
    - Witness, Tigers in Red Weather: Some Acad. Anecdotes, 1991 (Box 10)
    - The Hollins Critic, Review: Hagy's Hardware River Stories, 1992, Feb. (Box 10)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1992, Spring (Box 10)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1992, Summer (Box 10)
    - Literary Cavalcade, The Right Thing to Do at the Time, 1992, Sept. (Box 10)
    - ANQ: A Quarterly Journal of Short Articles, Notes, and Reviews, Soil of Hope, 1992, Oct. (Box 10)
    - The World and I, Whistling in the Dark, 1992, Nov. (Box 10)
    - The Sewanee Review, Creative Writing and American Publishing Now, 1992, Fall (Box 10)
    - Chronicles, Coveting thy Neighbor's Property, 1992, Dec. (Box 10)
    - The Sewanee Review, Tanks, 1992, Winter (2 copies) (Box 10)
    - Weber Studies, The Gift, 1992, Winter (Box 10)
    - The Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings Journal of Florida Literature, The Last Brother, 1992 (Box 10)
    - A New Geography of Poets, The Long and the Short of It, 1992 (Box 10)
    - The Wedding Cake in the Middle of the Road, (uncorrected proof copy), 1992 (Box 10)
    - Witness, Locker Room Talk, 1992 (Box 10)
    - College English, The Craft so Long to Learn, 1993, April (Box 10)
    - The World and I, The Character of Saints, 1993, Apr. (Box 10)
    - Michigan Quarterly Review, A Letter to Carolyn See, 1993, Spring (Box 10)
    - Chronicles, Ghosts, 1993, Sept. (Box 10)
    - The Southern California Anthology, Crowfoot, 1993 (Box 10)
    - The Magi, private printing for Christmas from the Garrett family, undated (Box 10)
    - Another Little Magazine, Art is Long..., undated (Box 10)
    - Folders of short stories: (undated)
      - Cold Ground Was my Bed Last Night (Box 10)
      - Double Exposure (Box 10)
      - The Faculty Wife (Box 10)
      - First Visit to the Land of Giants (Box 10)
      - The Last of the Buffalo Hunters (Box 10)
      - Our Lady Godiva (Box 10)
      - Philadelphia City Troop (Box 10)
      - The Poet in Real Life (Box 10)
      - The Return (Box 10)
      - Shooting Star (Box 10)
      - Texarkana was a Crazy Town (Box 10)
      - The Way Real Money Smells (Box 10)
- Biographical Data, 1965-1993
  Articles and other pieces offering information on Garrett's life and career as writer and English professor. Arranged in chronological order. Biographical information may also be found in the Clippings Series.
  - Technical details for The Playground, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Literary Landmarks of Princeton, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Latitudes, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Calliope's Comments, 1969, Nov.; 1971, May (Box 10)
  - Metro Hampton Roads, 1971, Dec.-Jan. (Box 10)
  - Broken Ink, George Garrett, 1971 (Box 10)
  - The South Carolina Review, Interview with Garrett, 1973, Nov. (Box 10)
  - The Penny Dreadful, Interview with George Garrett, 1975, Fall/Winter (Box 10)
  - Bulletin of Bibliography, 1981, Jan.-Mar. (Box 10)
  - The Student, 1981 (Box 10)
  - The South Carolina Review, interview, 1984, Spring (Box 10)
  - Quarterly West, George Garrett: An Interview, 1985, May (Box 10)
  - Poets and Writers, 1990, Jan./Feb. (Box 10)
  - Hollins, 1992, May (Box 10)
  - The Hill School Bulletin, 1992, Summer (Box 10)
  - The Iron Mountain Review, 1993, Spring (Box 10)
- Periodicals Series, 1960-1993 and undated
  Literary periodicals and popular magazines which do not have George Garrett's writings in them. Most contain an article or work of fiction (many are narratives by Southern writers), but some are also not marked in any way to indicate what was of interest to Garrett or the collector of this material, Stuart Wright. Arranged in alphabetical order by periodical title.
  - Ab Ovo (Box 11)
  - Albemarle, 1992, Aug./Sept. (Box 11)
  - The Bellingham Review, 1983, Fall (Box 11)
  - Blue Ox Review, 1985, Winter (Box 11)
  - Calliope's Comments, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Cargoes, 1979, Spring (Box 11)
  - Coda, 1982, Apr.-May (Box 11)
  - Denver Quarterly, 1985, Fall (Box 11)
  - Film News, 1970, Sept. (Box 11)
  - Film Scripts One, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Film Scripts Two, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Film Scripts Three, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Film Scripts Four, 1972 (Box 11)
  - The Georgia Review, 1969 (Box 11)
  - The Georgia Review, 1971 (Box 11)
  - The Georgia Review, 1986 Fall (Box 11)
  - The Georgia Review, 1990 (Box 11)
  - The Holiday Guide to Rome, Revised, 1976 (Box 11)
  - The Holiday Guide to Rome, New Edition, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Hollins, Writer's Reunion, 1987, Jan. (Box 11)
  - Monmouth Review, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Nassau Literary Review, 1975, Winter/Spring (Box 11)
  - National Review, 1986, 7 Nov. (Box 11)
  - Newsweek, 1964, 1 June (Box 11)
  - The North American Review, 1980, Mar. (Box 11)
  - The Ohio Review, 1979, Spring/Summer (Box 11)
  - Ploughshares, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Poets and Writers, 1990, Sept./Oct. (Box 11)
  - Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1969, 22 Apr. (Box 11)
  - Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1986, 10 Dec. (Box 11)
  - Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1990, 18 Apr. (Box 11)
  - Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Publishers Weekly, 1986, 12 Dec. (Box 11)
  - Readings by Young Poets, [19--], 6 May (Box 11)
  - Rome, A Holiday Magazine Travel Guide, 1960 (Box 11)
  - Sandlapper, 1975, Sept. (Box 11)
  - Sandlapper, 1976, Apr.-May. (Box 11)
  - The Sewanee Review, 1990, Spring (Box 11)
  - Society for Literature and Science, 1986, Aug. (Box 11)
  - The South Carolina Review, 1992, Fall (Box 11)
  - Southern Magazine, 1988, Dec. (Box 11)
  - The Student, 1980, Spring (Box 11)
  - The Texas Review, Review: The Succession, 1983, Fall/Winter (Box 11)
  - University of Virginia Alumni News, 1986, Nov./Dec. (Box 12)
  - The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1985, Spring (Box 12)
  - The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1992, Autumn (Box 12)
  - The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1993, Spring (Box 12)
  - Writers in Residence and Some Resident Writers, 1987-1988, Fall/Winter (limited edition keepsake pamphlet) (Box 12)
- Manuscripts, 1961-1965 and undated
  A few items of correspondence, film scripts, and various drafts and proofs. Series is not arranged in any particular order.
  - Correspondence (Box 12)
  - Scripts from final scene of The Young Lovers (Box 12)
  - The Young Lovers (script)
    - 1st draft screenplay, 1962, 12 Mar. (Box 12)
    - Revised treatment, 1962, 29 Jan. (Box 12)
    - Notes, undated (Box 12)
    - Screenplay, undated (Box 12)
    - Treatment, 1961, 11 Dec. (Box 12)
    - Script, 1962, 3 Nov. (Box 12)
    - Screenplay, 1963, 28 Feb. (Box 12)
    - Screenplay (heavily annotated--director's copy?), 1963, 20 Aug. (Box 12)
    - Screenplay, 1962, 28 Nov. (Box 12)
    - Screenplay, 1962, 9 Aug. (Box 12)
    - Publicity and miscellaneous documents, undated (Box 12)
  - The Scarlet Letter, Acts I, II, and III (Box 12)
  - The Binge (screenplay) 1965, 17 Mar. (Box 12)
  - The Magic Striptease (2 copies) (Box 12)
  - Don't You Remember that Time in Florida, one-act play (Box 12)
  - The Modern Coach: A New Breed? (Box 12)
  - The Sibyl (Box 12)
  - My Brother Death (Box 12)
  - The Playground (Box 12)
  - The Debutante (screenplay), 1965, 13 July (Box 13)
  - Stories from The Transatlantic Review (Box 13)
  - The Magic Striptease (uncorrected proof) (Box 13)
  - Poison Pen (uncorrected proof) (Box 13)
- Photographs, circa 1960s
  - The Young Lovers (movie publicity photos) (Box 13)
- Clippings, 1961-1990 and undated
  Clippings with writings by Garrett or articles of related interest. Series is not arranged in any order.
  - Poultry, A Magazine of Voice (Box 13)
    - 1961-1989 (Box 13)
    - 1990-1993, and undated (Box 13)
  - The Washington Post Book World, 1990, 3 Jun. (Box 13)
  - The Observer, 1989 Apr. (Box 13)
  - Hollins Columns
    - 1969, 16 Sept. (Box 13)
    - 1969, 23 Sept. (Box 13)
    - 1969, 7 Oct. (Box 13)
    - 1969, 21 Oct. (Box 13)
    - 1969, 18 Nov. (Box 13)
    - 1969, 9 Dec. (Box 13)
    - 1970, 24 Mar. (Box 13)
    - 1962, 29 Apr. (Box 13)
  - The Cavalier Daily
    - 1963, 1 Nov. (Box 13)
    - 1967, 1 Apr. (Box 13)
    - 1966, 27 Oct. (Box 13)
    - 1963, 7 Nov. (Box 13)
    - 1967, 14 Mar. (Box 13)
    - 1967, 3 Mar. (Box 13)
    - 1967, 15 Feb. (Box 13)
    - 1966, 25 Oct. (Box 13)
    - 1963, 8 Nov. (Box 13)
  - Chicago Tribune, The Arts, 1984, 3 June (Box 13)
  - The Daily Progress, 1966, 9 Dec. (Box 13)
  - The Daily Progress, 1967, 10 Feb. (Box 13)
  - The World News, 1970, 23 June (Box 13)
- Printed Materials, 1960-1989 and undated
  Miscellaneous printed materials not fitting the Writings and Speeches or Periodicals Series. Series is not arranged in any particular order.
  - Spring Poetry Festival material from Wesleyan, 1960, April/May (Box 13)
  - Poster from Hollins College Literary Festival, undated (Box 13)
  - A Lion's Cubs..., CHALFA program honoring Antonia Fraser, 1989 (Box 13)
  - At Home in History, CHALFA speech, 1989 (Box 13)
  - The Playground, 1964 (Box 13)
  - Garden Spot, USA, 1962 (Box 13)
  - Jacket Proofs, undated (Box 13)
- Oversize Materials
  - Harper's Bazaar, The Rivals, 1958, Feb. (2 copies) (Box 14)
  - Associated Writing Programs Newsletter, 1975, May (Box 14)
  - The New York Times Book Review, 1986, 26 Oct. (Box 14)
  - Jacket designs for novels, undated (Box 14)
  - Preview poster for The Playground, undated (Box 14)
  - The Observer, 1992 (Box 14)
  - The Orlando Sentinel, Storyteller Garrett: A Stickler for Detail, 1984, 24 May (Box 14)
  - The Young Lovers, Continuity sketches, undated (Box 14)